# **Joyce Shen**

Passionate product designer with over 2 years of experience working in cross-functional teams to conduct user research and design strategic products for clients. Team player with strong communication skills, outside-the-box ideas, user-centered thinking, and an eye for detail.

#### joyceshen.me

joyceshen0@gmail.com

## **Experience**

# UI/UX Design Co-op / U.S. Bank

August 2022 - December 2022 / Atlanta, GA

 Administered surveys and conducted desk research to illustrate user journeys in end-of-life financial planning

# Design Bootcamp Instructor / Bits of Good

June 2022 - Present / Atlanta, GA

 Led lectures, prepared curriculum, and provided individual guidance to product design learners

# Design Intern / Roblox

May 2022 - August 2022 / San Mateo, CA

- Presented a short- and long-term design vision for collaboration in game creation, guided by findings from leading user interviews, surveys, usability tests, and stakeholder meetings
- Led design support for an improved file management tool that was released to Roblox's 8+ million game creators

# **UX Design Intern / Lacework**

May 2021 - August 2021 / San Jose, CA

- Redesigned a workflow for creating cloud security reports, used by thousands of security executives
- Overhauled Lacework's dark mode design system, ensuring compliance with accessibility standards

## Product Designer / Bits of Good

January 2021 - December 2022 / Atlanta, GA

- Collaborated in cross-functional teams to develop powerful web apps for nonprofits advancing social good
- Solutions have benefited children of incarcerated mothers, nonprofit directors, and Georgia Tech's 40,000 students

## **UI & Digital Coordinator / EFBA**

June 2020 - November 2020 / San Francisco, CA

 Drove design and implementation of a new staff portal and a website log-in system

#### **Education**

## Georgia Institute of Technology

**BS** Computer Science

August 2019 – May 2023 Atlanta, GA 4.0 GPA, Faculty Honors Concentrations: People and Media

#### **Skills**

## Design

UI Design User Experience Design User Research Usability Testing Wireframes + Prototypes Design Systems

#### **Tools**

Figma
Sketch
Adobe XD
Adobe Photoshop
GitHub
Confluence

#### Code

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Java, C, C#, Python
Frameworks: React, D3.js, p5.js

(Processing)